Ariel Lima Andrade

Eskilstuna, Sweden +46 73 705 54 22 https://sudoariel.github.io lima.ariel97@gmail.com

https://github.com/sudoariel

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ariellima/

ABOUT ME

I love programming and challenges. My professors and employers have commended me for my high level of responsibility, teamwork, proactivity, problem solving skills and my ability to master new skills quickly. I am extremely motivated in overcoming challenges, learning new concepts and working well as a part of a team where we are able to share experiences and optimize results.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MAR 2022 - CURRENT (FT)

Volvo Construction Equipment Android Platform Engineer

Design and implementation in Android OS for machines infotainment systems. Android Security Internals (SELinux, AVB, OTA, APK signing, Qualcomm Secure Boot/eFuse), Android Platform Components (services, providers, applications) and CI/CD environment (Jenkins).

AUG 202I - FEB 2022 (FT)

Ford Motor Company Android Automotive OS Developer

Android Operating System modification and extension for custom vehicle hardware. Java/Kotlin application development for Android Automotive. Embedded Android/Linux systems.

JULY 2020 – JULY 2021 (FT)

Ford Motor Company Software Developer Analyst

Desktop, mobile and automotive embedded systems development. Vehicle modules prototypes development. Android Automotive embedded (AOSP). Programming languages: C/C++/C#/Java/Python.

JUNE 2019 - JULY 2020 (PT)

Ford Motor Company Software Developer Intern

Computer Engineering Intern in Software Team at Ford South America. Embedded and desktop software development.

 $OCT\ 2018-DEC\ 2018\ \ (PT)$

SENAI BAHIA Technical Advisor

Technical training specialized in PLC and HMI programming and FESTO MPS assembly and commissioning for Mechatronics competitors of the WorldSkills Competition 2019 in Kazan, Russia.

JUNE 2016 – JUNE 2017 (PT)

SENAI CIMATEC - Industrial Automation *Technical trainee*

Training for the WorldSkills Selective Abu Dhabi 2017 as a competitor: PLC and HMI programming (Siemens), assembly, maintenance and commissioning in integrated manufacturing systems (FESTO).

EDUCATION

2017 - CURRENT B.E. Computer Engineering

Electrical & Computer Engineer Federal University of Bahia (UFBA)

2014 – 2016 A.S. Electrotechnology

Technical School SENAI Cimatec

AWARDS

2021 Cost Award and Recognition

Ford Motor Company

2020 VCSE Leadership Awards

Ford Motor Company

2020 VCSE People's Choice Awards

Ford Motor Company

2019 VCSE Excellence Awards

Ford Motor Company

2017 Robustness Award

Brazilian Robotics Olympiad (OBR)

2016 Runner-up in Mechatronics

Selective WorldSkills Abu Dhabi 2017

COMPUTER SKILLS

BEGINNER HTML, CSS, Javascript
INTERMEDIATE C, C++, Shell, Groovy
ADVANCED C#, Java, Kotlin, Python

LANGUAGE SKILLS

ENGLISH Advanced level
SPANISH Intermediate level
PORTUGUESE Native speaker

SKILLS

Problem-solving

Problems are inevitable in daily work routine. I feel motivated when new challenges arise, which opens space for my creativity and innovativeness.

Teamwork

I've worked as a team member on several engineering projects where we were successful and awarded for bringing innovative solutions.

Willingness to learn

I am an active learner interested in learning new concepts and technologies and also expanding the knowledge I have on topics that I am familiar with.